Ryan Sullivan Kelley | 860-916-7174 | RyanK@InfinitumDev.com

Professional Summary

Adaptable and resourceful software engineer with three years of work experience in fast-paced, dynamic environments. Proficient with object-oriented programming and working with agile project structures, including Scrum and Extreme Programming. Strengths include:

- Ruby, JavaScript, Python
- Rails and MVC frameworks
- Agile Methodologies
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Responsive UI Design

- Continuous Integration
- Test-Driven Development
- Information Security
- Relational Databases
- Economic Analysis

Technical Proficiency

Application Frameworks: Rails, Lotus, Sinatra, RubyMotion, AngularJS, Node.JS, Bottle, Flask Databases and ORM: ActiveRecord, Mongoid, MongoMapper, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite Languages and Specifications: Ruby, JavaScript, AJAX, Coffeescript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Python, RSpec, SQL, Swift, Unix Shell

Operating Systems: Mac OS X, Unix, iOS, Windows 7+

Security: Devise, OAuth, Token-Based Authentication, Role-Based Authorization, Public Key Encryption, RSA, PGP/GPG, Symmetric Encryption, OpenSSL, OTP/Nonce, SSH, SSL/TLS

Tools and Services: cURL, JQ, NMAP, Wireshark, Heroku, AWS, Virtual Box, Xcode, Balsamiq, CharlesProxy, TMUX, MacVim, Git, RubyMine, Eclipse

Professional Experience

Infinitum Development, Dallas, TX (Remote)

Agile Software Engineer, November 2014 – Present

I am the primary developer of web applications at Infinitum. I work closely with managers and support teams in a high-velocity, agile environment to deliver software on one and two-week sprint schedules. At the end of every sprint, I lead a live demonstration of the latest software release to clients via streaming video conference. In addition to coding, I am responsible for most cloud architecture design, and I collaborate with other development teams to integrate desktop and mobile software with the cloud applications I build.

Web Gem Development, Arlington, VA

Agile Software Consultant, February 2014 – Present

I am the founder and lead developer at this consulting firm. In less than two years, I have successfully provided agile development and project management services to six different businesses. I provide each client with a one-stop, full-cycle solution for their software projects, beginning with design, and ending with testing and deployment.

Dev Bootcamp, Chicago, IL

Pairing Coach, November 2013 – February 2014

I mentored and helped teach new boots introductory programming with Ruby and Javascript before their arrival at the DBC space.

Recent Projects

uOontrol Cloud Platform

- Secure online shopping platform based on novel, three-factor authentication system and EMV technology
- Used Ruby on Rails to build uQontrol platform's cloud server
- Implemented the pairing, purchase authorization, key initialization, authentication and registration APIs
- Secured authentication system using RSA and AES encryption, industry-standard symmetric and public-key encryption technology
- Translated backlog user stories into wireframes and functional diagrams at the beginning of each sprint
- Protected server from replay attacks using time-stamped nonce in authentication procedure
- Built services for iOS and desktop client applications using JSON-RPC over HTTPS
- Extensive processing, encrypting, obfuscating and encoding of data for secure consumption by remote clients
- Migrated Python code from prototype device pairing server to Ruby, used it as foundation for new pairing API
- Facilitated integration and product support by creating concise walkthroughs and documentation on technical architecture, system requirements
- Assisted in design and development of Qkey hardware initialization program and procedure
- Added Apple Push Notifications to Qkey iOS application and compiled app for beta testing with TestFlight
- Utilized sequence diagrams, UML and wireframes to model interaction, service logic, procedures and architecture
- Used cURL, OpenSSL, Ruby and Unix Shell scripts to test production services from command line
- Created cloud server's standardized response structure with documented error and response codes
- Utilized velocity tracking and estimation to measure and improve productivity

uQontrol and Qkey Websites

- Created uQontrol platform customer-facing Rails website using Bootstrap, Coffeescript and Slim templates
- Built protected administration portal using ActiveAdmin, Devise authentication and role-based authorization
- Used Stripe API to create product ordering and redemption system
- Added order processing, inventory and shipment managing systems using FedEx API
- Assisted in the design and development of separate Qkey promotional/pre-orders website
- Protected sensitive data exchange on client-facing website using TLS encrypted connection

Dental Admin

- Rails application provides the foundation for medical practices to develop a web platform quickly
- Provides customizable patient management, registration and database admin system 'out of the box'
- HIPAA-compliant appointment request system with SMS message reminders

Atlantic Waterproofing

• Developed new corporate Rails website with responsive, engaging and navigable user interfaces

KarmaGrove

- Payment system that tracks a percentage of each transaction and donates it to a charity of merchant's choice
- Developed KarmaGrove website and payment processing system using Ruby on Rails

Education

Dev Bootcamp, Chicago, Illinois

Web Application Development, Graduated November 2013

- Rigorous agile web development immersion program utilizes lab setting modeled after workplace
- Committed 70-100 hours per week, for 3 months, developing countless programs

The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.

B.A. Economics, Graduated May 2012

• Perfect score for senior thesis, "Pitcher Productivity and the Major League Baseball Labor Market."